<jiaoran.wang@mail.mcgill.ca> | TEL: +86 16631181498 | Shanghai, China

Personal Website: https://jiaoranwang.github.io/home/

SUMMARY

Research Interests: Implantable Device Monitoring, Adaptive Wireless Antenna

etc.

of the sensor

Research Background: Machine Learning, Control, Automation, Bio-inspired Robot, Additive Manufacturing, Structural Design and Optimization.

06/2024 - Present	University of Glasgow • Postgraduate Student in Electrical and Electronics Engineering	Glasgow, United Kingdom
09/2022 - 09/2023	McGill University • Postgraduate Student in Bioengineering (Dropped out)	Montréal, Canada (remote study)
09/2019 - 05/2021	 University of Southern California (USC) M.S. in Mechanical Engineering. GPA: 3.84/4.0 	Los Angeles, USA
09/2015 - 07/2019	 Harbin Engineering University (HEU) B.E. in Aerospace Engineering (Flight Vehicle Design and Engineering) GPA: 3.42/4.0 (Major GPA: 3.46/4.0) 	Harbin, China

QUALIFICATIONS

	Programming Language:	MATLAB-Simulink (proficient), Python (good at data structure), R/RStudio(familiar),
		C/C++(familiar),
\diamond	Web Application Language:	HTML5, CSS3, PHP, JavaScript, SQL (familiar)
\diamond	CAD Software:	SolidWorks (proficient), Auto-CAD (proficient), UG-NX (familiar), CATIA (familiar)
\diamond	Simulation Software:	ABAQUS (proficient), ANSYS (proficient in APDL/FLUENT/CFX), COMSOL
		(familiar with Multiphysics)
\diamond	Equipment:	3D Printer(proficient), Laser Cutting Machine, CNC Machine and other machine tools,

Dissertation: Design and Experimental Study of Thermoelectric Structure in Aerospace Aircraft

EXPERIENCE			
06/2024 - Present	University of Glasgow Postgraduate Student in Electrical and Electronics Engineering	Glasgow, Scotland, United Kingdom	
10/2021 - 05/2024	 Algorithm Engineer, Huawei Technologies Co., Ltd. Junior Engineer. Engaged in research and design for advanced communication transmission system and networking products relating to 5G/5.5G technology, integrated the Large Language Model (LLM) and communication algorithm to realize parameter Cluster Analysis (CA) Desiged automated test frameworks for product performance testing optimization (Python) 5G Massive MIMO AAU (Active Antenna Unit) in the established sub-6 GHz frequency spectrum, base stations typically apply a high number of TX/RX antenna elements to serve multiple users with parallel data streams. This is known as multi-user MIMO (MU-MIMO). Key Performance Indicators (KPI) Platform Building 		
09/2022 - 09/2023 01/2021 - 06/2021	 Machine Learning Assisted Reconfigurable Metamaterials Remote Study Program Working on: Metamaterials (mechanical, phononic, acoustic etc.) Reconfigurable and Multistable metamaterials (multi-material) Nonlinear finite element concept (buckling, instability, nonlinear elasticit Inverse design using machine learning and differences with optimization. Colorimetric Pressure Sensing Device Fabrication (CAM Lab, USC) Graduate Research Assistant (Advisor: Prof. Hangbo Zhao) 	ear elasticity) timization.	
	• Experiment: convert the small thrust and pull force into the color rendering of the liquid film		

<jiaoran.wang@mail.mcgill.ca> | TEL: +86 16631181498 | Shanghai, China Personal Website: https://jiaoranwang.github.io/home/

Test and analysis: test and get the push and pull stress and sensor grayscale curve, used for micro sensor applications.

01/2020 - 05/2021

Bio-inspired Biped Robot Project (Brain-Body Dynamics Lab, USC)

Los Angeles, USA

Los Angeles, USA

Graduate Research Assistant (Advisor: Prof. Francisco Valero-Cuevas)

- Working on the design of biomechanical leg for Zero Moment Point calculation
- Using Machine Learning (KNN) module to architecture and artificial wearable sensor data analysis to predict the balanced pressure center position of the bionic robot. (see the publication)

01/2020 - 05/2020

Additive Manufacturing Research (CAM Lab, USC)

Directed Research (Advisor: Prof. Satyandra K. Gupta)

- Project: Additive Manufacturing 3D Printing of Conformal Antenna
- Using the 6-DOF industrial robot created by USC Advanced Manufacturing Center combined with fused deposition (FDM) method in 3D printing and path planning algorithm, addressed 3D printing of smooth curved conformal array antenna.
- Designed an Arduino Python UDP communication system for manually and remotely control for robot 3D printing with linear control involved.

09/2019 - 11/2019

Design Project on Automatic Test-tube Sorting System for YASKAWA

Course Project (Advisor: Prof. Satyandra K. Gupta)

- Conceived a design proposal using rollers and conveyers for rapid Test-tube Sorting System
- Designed OpenCV (visual image recognition technology) for tube identification.

01/2019 - 06/2019

Preparation and Thermal Properties of Carbon-based Mesoporous Phase Change Composites

Capstone Project (Advisor: Prof. Jia Yu)

- Conducted design and experimental study of *Thermoelectric Structure* in *Aerospace Aircraft*.
- Invented the thermoelectric piece architecture among annular thermoelectric module at gunship nozzle, and the temperature difference experiment was carried out
- Proposed a method to determine the optimal size based on the conversion efficiency extremum. Increased the thermoelectric conversion efficiency by 37.30% and the output power by 285.14%

2016 - 2019

Aircraft Model Aerodynamic Optimization (Aircraft Innovation Lab, HEU)

- Renovated the overall process of aircraft model manufacturing, including designing, painting with software like *Auto-CAD and UG*, mastered the use of *3D printing*.
- Studied the operation methods of milling machines, planers, lathes and grinding machines, miniaturesemiconductor spot welding and electric-arc welding, robot installment and operation, CNC machine tool programming and wire-electrode cutting, benchwork, etc.

11/2017 - 12/2018

Remote Research Projects Guided by Tsinghua University

Change

Harbin, China

Los Angeles, USA

<jiaoran.wang@mail.mcgill.ca> | TEL: +86 16631181498 | Shanghai, China
Parsonal Wahsita: https://ijiaoran.wang.github.jo/homa/

Personal Website: https://jiaoranwang.github.io/home/

Topic: Dynamic analysis and motion accuracy evaluation of multibody system with clearance mechanism considering uncertain parameters

Beijing, China

• Introduced OpenCV flow field modeling for flight environmental construction.

PUBLICATION

Darío Urbina-Meléndez, **Jiaoran Wang**, et al. "Estimating Center of Pressure of a Bipedal Mechanism Using Proprioceptive Synthetic Skin around its Ankles." 2021 43rd Annual International Conference of the IEEE Engineering in Medicine & Biology Society (EMBC).

INTERNSHIPS

06/2020 - 07/2020

BCG Virtual Experience Program (InsideSherpa 2020)

Participated in the open access Digital Technology Data Analytics Program Virtual Experience:

Categorize and process data structures.

Data visualization

02/2019 - 03/2019 China Academy of Launch Vehicle Technology (CALT)

Beijing, China

Worked in the structure of transportation rocket projector and participated in the unit part grinding and assembly process.

07/2018 - 09/2018 AVIC Shenyang Aircraft Co., Ltd.

Shenyang, China

• Visited the workshops of civil and military aviation and learnt practical aircraft manufacturing knowledge and skills as well as the differences in the procedures of manufacturing

EXCHANGE EXPERIENCE

 02/2018 - 03/2018
 International Programs in UC San Diego Extension
 San Diego, USA

 • Program: English for Engineering and Technology
 • Grade: A
 Minneapolis, USA

 01/2018 - 02/2018
 • Department: Chemical Engineering and Material Science
 Minneapolis, USA

• Core Courses: Reactor and reaction engineering, Chemical engineering laboratory, Numerical methods in chemical applications

LICENCES & CERTIFICATES

Issue Date 08/2020	Name Control of Mobile Robots	Issuing Organization Coursera (Georgia Institute of Technology)
08/2020	Data Processing and Feature Engineering with MATLAB ♦ Credential: https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/VQVCQZ8TKA8S	Coursera (MathWorks)
08/2020	Digital Manufacturing & Design	Coursera (The State University of New York)
07/2020	Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter tuning, Regularization and Optimization	Coursera (Deeplearning.ai)
06/2020	R Programming ♦ Credential: https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/HH6LDFV5BNJA	Coursera (Johns Hopkins University)

<jiaoran.wang@mail.mcgill.ca> | TEL: +86 16631181498 | Shanghai, China Personal Website: https://jiaoranwang.github.io/home/

05/2020

Python Data Structures

♦ Credential: https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/K2SS6NVE756G

Coursera (University of Michigan)

Introduction: Jiaoran